With your damp book up on edge, with all of the pages fanned out, it?s just as important now, as with your saturated book to have good air flow.
So once again, I'm going to turn the air filter on.
Of course you can use an oscillating fan.
It's important for you to have, if it?s a fan, for the air to be moving constantly and not just blowing directly on the book.
Unless the fan is across the room.
Because otherwise you could end up damaging the pages by bending them, perhaps, with the flow of air if it?s too strong.
So like the air filter, it?s a much lower speed of air, that coming through.
One thing that's very important to remember is you never ever want to have your book on its covers like this.
This is not going to do any good for your book, its going to pull it away from the spine here.
And it?s also going to damage the pages, because they are going to be flattened on the edges where they've been presses against the table.
So you always want to have your book up on end, spread out for it to dry.
One thing to remember though is that once you have it out on end, you don't need to check nearly as frequently with your damp book, as you do with your saturated or partially wet book.
Because for the most part is fairly dry.
However, you do need to come and flip the book once in a while.
This is to ensure that the pages, because they will be pulling just a little away from the spine.
Are not going to pull away entirely in one direction.
So as long as you keep flipping the book, then you are going to have much more even drying.
And this way it also ensures that the tops and bottoms of the pages aren't drying at a much slower pace than the rest of it.
Because they are against the bottom of your table.